Finding Aid for the Collection of Research Materials Related to Linguistic-Psychological Studies of Genie (pseudonym), 1895-2003, 1970-2003 LSC.0800
UCLA Library Special Collections
- 8. Research, ca. 1938-1994 (bulk 1970-1977)
  - 8E. Language, sleep, and social behaviors, 1962-1976 (bulk 1970-1976)
    - Bloom, Lois / Cognitive and linguistic aspects of early language development, 1972 November 21 (Box 63, Folder 10)
      Short course presented at American Speech and Hearing Association Convention in San Francisco, Calif.
    - Braff, Reba--Notes on observation and conference with H. Russell Haney, 1972 October 3 (Box 63, Folder 11)
    - Braff, Reba--Report to Crippled Children's Services, 1972 July 12 (Box 63, Folder 12)
    - Dodd, David H. and P. David Glanzer / Environmental factors in early language acquisition, 1973 September 25 (Box 63, Folder 13)
      Draft version.
    - Eisenson, Jon--Psychological and language evaluations of [Genie], 1973 June 12 (Box 63, Folder 14)
    - Frank, Sheldon M. / Children's language in free play situation, 1973 October 31 (Box 63, Folder 15)
      Includes cover letter to David Rigler.
    - Friedlander, Bernard Z.--Publications and reports, 1969-1974 (Box 63, Folder 16)
    - Gardner, Beatrice and R. Allen Gardner--Work on communication with chimpanzees, 1969-1973 (Box 63, Folder 17)
      Several articles and papers; includes references to Project Washoe.
    - Genie's language development, 1972 January 3-1974 March 6 (Box 63, Folder 18)
      Typed synopses of sessions with Genie.
    - Gestures and signs used by Genie, ca. 1973 (Box 64, Folder 1)
    - Gestures, phrases, and sentences used by Genie, 1973 March; undated (Box 64, Folder 2)
    - Gestures, phrases, and words used by Genie, 1971-1974 (Box 64, Folder 3)
    - Kirk, Samuel A.--Psychological assessment, 1971 July 16 (Box 64, Folder 4)
    - Kirk, Samuel A.--Transcription of meeting, 1971 February 2 (Box 64, Folder 5)
      Attended by Dr. Winifred Kirk, Dr. Samuel Kirk, Jean Butler, and David Rigler.
    - Kirk, Samuel A.--Various material regarding meeting follow-up, 1971 January 2-1971 July 6 (Box 64, Folder 6)
    - Krashen, Stephen--Various material, 1975 September 29 (Box 64, Folder 7)
      Includes correspondence and manuscripts.
    - Language acquisition by Genie, ca. 1974 November (Box 64, Folder 8)
      Synopsis of words used over four-year period.
    - Lowell Bouma / Is first language acquisition possible at age 39?, 1974 December 19 (Box 64, Folder 9)
      Copy sent to David Rigler. Includes cover letter.
    - Mitchell, Gillian and Jacquelin Schacter--Preliminary notes regarding the semantic analysis of Genie's speech, ca. 1972 (Box 64, Folder 10)
    - Natani and Shurley work on Genie's sleep psychophysiology, 1975 April 2-1975 June 11 (Box 64, Folder 11)
      Letters, memoranda, and journal articles.
    - Natani, Kirmach / Ontogeny of Sleep Disorders, 1975 May 9 (Box 64, Folder 12)
    - Notes and graph regarding Genie's sleep patterns, ca. 1971 (Box 64, Folder 13)
      Material from Dr. Jay Shurley.
    - Observed behaviorisms, 1974 November 20-1974 December 30 (Box 64, Folder 14)
    - Piagetian theory material, 1976 January 30 (Box 64, Folder 15)
    - Shurley, Jay T.--Various material, 1962-1970 (Box 64, Folder 16)
      Includes extended consultation report, suggested amendment to request for approval clinical investigation, and various articles authored or co-authored by Dr. Shurley.
    - Shurley, Jay T.--Various material, 1970 November 19-1971 May 10 (Box 64, Folder 17)
      Includes initial correspondence regarding Shurley's interest in the case.
    - Tantrum behavior scales observed by Marilyn Rigler, 1973 June-1975 April (Box 64, Folder 18)
    - Testing notes on Genie's verbalization, 1974 December 30 (Box 64, Folder 19)
    - Transcriptions of language comprehension testing, 1971 November 29-1973 April 23 (Box 64, Folder 20)
    - Words said by Genie as transcribed by Tribbey Miller, ca. 1973 (Box 64, Folder 21)
  - 8F. Miscellaneous, 1938-1977 (bulk 1970-1977)
    Subseries consists of pedagogical material, documentation from a similar case study, correspondence, various reports, cards and letters from the public, and other miscellaneous material.
    - Mansfield Training School: Manual Language Training Program, 1972 November 30 (Box 64, Folder 22)
    - Blank, Marion, 1975 February 3-1975 May 23 (Box 64, Folder 23)
      Correspondence, notes, and material on imagery, problem solving, counter factual attributes.
    - Block, Jack and Jeanne H. Block / Ego Development and the Provenance of Thought: A Longitudinal Study of Ego and Cognitive Development in Young Children, 1973 January (Box 64, Folder 24)
      Progress report for NIMH grant number MH 16080.
    - Case study--Annabelle Barton case study clinical observations, 1939 January-1940 March (Box 64, Folder 25)
      Student clinician reports on observations of speech-impaired child with similar history to Genie.
    - Case study--Annabelle Barton case study clinical observations, 1938 November 20-1962 July 26 (Box 65, Folder 1)
    - Case study--Annabelle Barton case study microfilm, 1939 January-1940 March (Box 65, Folder 2)
      1 reel.
    - Committee on Clinical Investigations and Publications--Various material, 1970 June 6-1976 March 19 (Box 65, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence from unknown author regarding Genie's eye movements, ca. 1973 (Box 65, Folder 4)
      Two extant pages.
    - Freides, David / Nosology for disorders of behavior, emotion and learning based on organism--environment interaction, 1973 August 30 (Box 65, Folder 5)
    - Garmezy, Nomran--Various material on schizophrenia and children, 1966-1972 (Box 65, Folder 6)
    - Genie's typing, 1974 April 2 (Box 66, Folder 1)
    - Johnston, Judith / Spatial notions and the child's use of locatives in an elicitation task, 1973 April (Box 66, Folder 2)
    - Kagen, Jerome--Harvard University, 1973 February 14-1973 June 13 (Box 66, Folder 3)
      Correspondence, clippings, and paper entitled "Cross-Cultural Perspectives on Early Development."
    - Knox, Susan--Play scale material, 1968 (Box 66, Folder 4)
    - Knox, Susan--Re-evaluation of sensory integration report, 1974 July 15 (Box 66, Folder 5)
    - Knox, Susan--Occupational therapy report, 1977 August 18 (Box 66, Folder 6)
    - Krashen, Stephen--Note on creativity and conjugate lateral eye movement, ca. 1974 (Box 66, Folder 7)
    - Krashen, Stephen--Papers, notes, and reports, 1972 (Box 66, Folder 8)
    - Letters and cards sent by strangers to Genie, 1970 November (Box 66, Folder 9)
      Unanswered cards and letters.
    - Marshall, John--Various material, 1973 October-December (Box 66, Folder 10)
      Memo concerning Genie and handwritten notes.
    - Material from Asahide Research Institute for the Mentally Retarded, 1963, 1970 (Box 66, Folder 11)
      Material regarding special education for mentally retarded.
    - Material from National Society for the Prevention of Cruelty to Children (No. Ireland), 1957 November 27; 1958 December 18 (Box 66, Folder 12)
      Photocopies of letters regarding case of Kevin Halfpenny.
    - Material regarding articles about Genie appearing in Mental Health Development newsletter, 1974 October 1 (Box 66, Folder 13)
    - Material regarding using sign language with Genie, 1974 May 2-1974 September 3 (Box 66, Folder 14)
      Work with Marina McIntyre and Larry Solow.
    - Pedagogical note by Marilyn Rigler regarding paying Genie with pennies, ca. 1972 (Box 66, Folder 15)
    - Publication--"Mental Health Laws", 1970 (Box 66, Folder 16)
      Laws for the state of California.
    - Rigler, Marilyn--Draft text of working with Genie, ca. 1975 (Box 66, Folder 17)
      Typed and hand edited document.
    - Title V ESEA Reading Project material, 1970 (Box 66, Folder 18)
      Remedial reading programs for institutionalized juveniles.
    - Transcription--Staff meeting regarding Aphasia Institute, Stanford, 1973 May 23 (Box 66, Folder 19)
    - Various letters and card sent by strangers to Genie with responses sent by Howard Hansen, 1970 November-1971 July 6 (Box 66, Folder 20)
    - Various material gathered by Victoria Fromkin and Susan Curtiss, 1971-1972 (Box 67, Folder 1)
      Includes progress notes and observational logs.
  - 8G. Notes, ca. 1970-1994 (bulk 1970-1977)
    Subseries consists mainly of observational notes of Genie and her behavior. Includes hospital nursing staff notes and research team notebooks which, in some cases, were typed and collated according to date.
    - Notes by hospital staff on Genie's care, 1970 July 20-1970 November 26 (Box 67, Folder 2)
      Includes nursing care plan.
    - Butler, Jean and nursing staff--Observational notes on Genie, 1970 November (Box 67, Folder 3)
    - Kent, James--Progress notes, 1970 November 6-1971 July 12 (Box 67, Folder 4)
    - Butler, Jean and nursing staff--Observational notes on Genie, 1970 December (Box 67, Folder 5)
    - Butler, Jean--Notes and observations, 1970 December-1971 May (Box 67, Folder 6)
    - Miscellaneous manuscripts and grant application notes, ca. 1971 (Box 67, Folder 7)
    - Miscellaneous notes, ca. 1971 (Box 67, Folder 8)
    - Miscellaneous notes by various unidentified authors, ca. 1971 (Box 67, Folder 9)
    - Plans for Genie, ca. 1971 (Box 67, Folder 10)
      Unidentified author.
    - Regarding rehabilitation efforts, ca. 1971 (Box 67, Folder 11)
    - Rigler, David--Miscellaneous notes, ca. 1971 (Box 67, Folder 12)
      Various handwritten pages and two notebooks on various topics.
    - Rigler, David--Notes on various topics, ca. 1971 (Box 67, Folder 13)
    - Rigler, David--Regarding Dr. Ursula Bellugi, ca. 1971 April 16 (Box 68, Folder 1)
    - Handwritten notes regarding videotapes that have been transcribed, 1971 (Box 68, Folder 2)
    - Nursing staff notes, 1971 January (Box 68, Folder 3)
    - Butler, Jean--Observational notes, 1971 January-March (Box 68, Folder 4)
    - Rigler, David--Notes from discussion with Peter Wolff., 1971 January 19 (Box 68, Folder 5)
    - Typed collation of notes from various authors, 1971 January 21; 1971 February 2 (Box 68, Folder 6)
    - Rigler, David--Observational notes, 1971 February 5; 1971 March 6; 1971 November 24 (Box 68, Folder 7)
    - Rigler, David and Jean Butler--Observational notes on Genie, 1971 April 1, 9, 30 (Box 68, Folder 8)
    - Rigler, David--Observational notes on Peabody and Leiter testing, 1971 April 9 (Box 68, Folder 9)
    - Handwritten notes on Genie's behavior, 1971 April; 1971 July; undated (Box 68, Folder 10)
    - Rigler, David and Jean Butler--Observational notes on Genie, 1971 May (Box 68, Folder 11)
    - Stenographer's note book, 1971 June 4 (Box 68, Folder 12)
    - Rigler, David and Marilyn Rigler--Observational notes on Genie, 1971 August (Box 68, Folder 13)
    - Handwritten notes on Genie's behavior, 1971 August-December (Box 68, Folder 14)
    - Typed collation of notes from various authors, 1971 September 1-1971 October 2 (Box 68, Folder 15)
    - Typed collation of notes from various authors, 1971 October (Box 68, Folder 16)
    - Rigler, Marilyn--Observational notes, 1971 October 21 (Box 68, Folder 17)
    - Observational notes on Genie, 1971 October 28-1971 November 24 (Box 68, Folder 18)
    - Typed notes regarding observations of Genie by various team members, 1971 October 28-1973 October 8 (Box 68, Folder 19)
    - Typed notes regarding observations of Genie by various team members, 1971 November (Box 68, Folder 20)
      Also includes transcription of David Rigler interview with Irene Wiley.
    - Rigler, David--French Pictorial Test of Intelligence with Genie., 1971 November 3 (Box 68, Folder 21)
    - Rigler, Marilyn--Observational notes, 1971 November 20-25 (Box 68, Folder 22)
      Typed log of Genie's behavior.
    - Rigler, David--Stenographer's notebook, ca. 1971 November 27 (Box 68, Folder 23)
    - Various transcriptions and observations, 1971 November-1973 March (Box 69, Folder 1)
    - Typed collation of notes from various authors, 1971 December (Box 69, Folder 2)
    - Rigler, Marilyn--Observational notes, 1971 December 8-31 (Box 69, Folder 3)
      Handwritten log of Genie's behavior.
    - Assorted observational notes on Genie, 1971-1972 (Box 69, Folder 4)
    - Rigler, Marilyn--Past working papers/rough drafts, 1971-1972 (Box 69, Folder 5)
    - Elkind, David--Notes, ca. 1972 (Box 69, Folder 6)
    - Rigler, Marilyn--Miscellaneous notes, ca. 1972 (Box 69, Folder 7)
    - Rigler, David--Handwritten notes, ca. 1972 (Box 69, Folder 8)
    - Rigler, Marilyn--Transcriptions from dictation, 1972 January (Box 69, Folder 9)
    - Rigler, Marilyn--Observational notes, 1972 January 1-12 (Box 69, Folder 10)
    - Wiley, Irene--Letters to the Rigler's describing Genie visits and behavior, 1972 January 25-1975 March 21 (Box 69, Folder 11)
    - Typed notes, 1972 February (Box 70, Folder 1)
    - Typed notes, 1972 March (Box 70, Folder 2)
    - Handwritten notes on Genie's behavior, 1972 March-September (Box 70, Folder 3)
    - Typed notes, 1972 April (Box 70, Folder 4)
    - Typed notes, 1972 May (Box 70, Folder 5)
    - Rigler, Marilyn--Notebooks, 1972 May 3-1973 February 8 (Box 70, Folder 6)
    - Typed notes, 1972 June (Box 70, Folder 7)
    - A visit with [Genie], 1972 June 15 (Box 70, Folder 8)
    - Typed notes, 1972 July (Box 70, Folder 9)
    - Various authors--Notebooks logging Genie's behavior, 1972 July; 1972 September (Box 70, Folder 10)
      Also includes a loose-leaf picture drawn by Genie.
    - Rigler, Marilyn--Notebooks, 1972 July 6-1974 January 20 (Box 71, Folder 1)
      Six composition notebooks.
    - Curtiss, Susan--Session with Genie, 1972 July 17 (Box 71, Folder 2)
    - Typed notes, 1972 August (Box 71, Folder 3)
    - Rigler, David and Marilyn Rigler--Miscellaneous notes, 1972 September (Box 71, Folder 4)
    - Typed notes, 1972 September (Box 71, Folder 5)
    - Various authors--Notebooks logging Genie's behavior, 1972 September 14-1973 March 23 (Box 71, Folder 6)
    - Material from Childrens Hospital of Los Angeles meeting, 1972 September 23-24 (Box 71, Folder 7)
    - Typed notes, 1972 October (Box 71, Folder 8)
    - Typed collation of notes from various authors, 1972 November (Box 71, Folder 9)
    - Typed collation of notes from various authors, 1972 December (Box 71, Folder 10)
    - Curtiss, Susan--Progress notes, 1972 December 26 (Box 71, Folder 11)
    - Assorted handwritten notes, ca. 1973 (Box 72, Folder 1)
    - Genie's communication techniques, ca. 1973 (Box 72, Folder 2)
    - Notes regarding Genie's left and right hemisphere functions, ca. 1973 (Box 72, Folder 3)
    - Rigler, David--Regarding recognition testing, ca. 1973 (Box 72, Folder 4)
    - Rigler, Marilyn--Synopsis regarding Genie's growth and socialization, ca. 1973 (Box 72, Folder 5)
    - Various hand written notes, ca. 1973 (Box 72, Folder 6)
    - Rigler, David--Miscellaneous notes, 1973 (Box 72, Folder 7)
    - Typed collation of notes from various authors, 1973 January (Box 72, Folder 8)
    - Rigler, David--Miscellaneous notes, 1973 January 4; 1973 June 4, 18; undated (Box 72, Folder 9)
    - Meeting minutes prepared by Victoria Fromkin, 1973 January 12 (Box 72, Folder 10)
    - Typed collation of notes from various authors, 1973 February (Box 72, Folder 11)
      Includes photocopy of record form of Stanford-Binet Intelligence Scale
    - Rigler, Marilyn--Notebooks, 1973 February 8-1973 March 21 (Box 72, Folder 12)
    - Rigler, Marilyn--Notes and progress reports, 1973 February 22; 1974 May-October (Box 72, Folder 13)
    - Rigler, David--Observations and interactions with Genie, 1973 February 23; 1975 January-February (Box 72, Folder 14)
    - Typed collation of notes from various authors, 1973 March (Box 72, Folder 15)
    - Various authors--Notebooks logging Genie's behavior, 1973 March 1-1973 August 1 (Box 72, Folder 16)
    - Transcription of exchange between Marilyn Rigler and Genie, 1973 March 21 (Box 72, Folder 17)
    - Typed collation of notes from various authors, 1973 April (Box 72, Folder 18)
    - Handwritten notes on Genie's behavior, 1973 May (Box 73, Folder 1)
    - Typed notes from various authors, 1973 May (Box 73, Folder 2)
    - Typed collation of notes from various authors, 1973 June (Box 73, Folder 3)
    - Hearn, Sharon--Original notes, 1973 June 19-1974 June 22 (Box 73, Folder 4)
    - Hearn, Sharon--Notes and workbooks, 1973 June 19-1974 June 26 (Box 73, Folder 5)
      Includes drawings by Genie.
    - Hearn, Sharon--Handwritten notes regarding sessions with Genie, 1973 June 25, 27, 29 (Box 73, Folder 6)
    - Typed collation of notes from various authors, 1973 July (Box 73, Folder 7)
    - Observation Notes--Unknown author, 1973 July 9-1974 October 1 (Box 73, Folder 8)
      Photocopies of typed notes.
    - Typed collation of notes from various authors, 1973 August (Box 73, Folder 9)
    - Various authors--Notebooks logging Genie's behavior, 1973 August 3-1974 March 15 (Box 73, Folder 10)
    - Various authors--Notebooks logging Genie's behavior, 1973 August 3-1975 April 8 (Box 73, Folder 11)
    - Typed collation of notes from various authors, 1973 September (Box 74, Folder 1)
    - Typed collation of notes from various authors, 1973 October (Box 74, Folder 2)
    - Typed collation of notes from various authors, 1973 November (Box 74, Folder 3)
    - Typed collation of notes from various authors, 1973 December (Box 74, Folder 4)
    - Braff, Reba--Notebook logging Genie's behavior, 1973 December 26-1974 January 31 (Box 74, Folder 5)
    - Rigler, David and Marilyn Rigler--Miscellaneous notes, ca. 1974 (Box 74, Folder 6)
    - Typed collation of notes from various authors, 1974 January (Box 74, Folder 7)
    - Rigler, Marilyn--Notebooks, 1974 January 21-1974 November 30 (Box 74, Folder 8)
    - Typed collation of notes from various authors, 1974 February (Box 74, Folder 9)
      File also included progress report card from Sophia T. Salvin School dated February 1, 1974.
    - Notes on Genie's money counting skills, 1974 February 22 (Box 74, Folder 10)
    - Typed collation of notes from various authors, 1974 March (Box 74, Folder 11)
    - Rigler, Marilyn--Observation matrix of Genie's behavior, 1974 March 6 (Box 74, Folder 12)
    - Typed notes from various authors, 1974 April (Box 75, Folder 1)
    - Typed notes from various authors, 1974 May (Box 75, Folder 2)
    - Observational notes--Unknown author, 1974 May 13-June 6 (Box 75, Folder 3)
    - Rigler, Marilyn--Notebooks, 1974 May 17-1975 May 16 (Box 75, Folder 4)
    - Typed collation of notes from various authors, 1974 June (Box 75, Folder 5)
    - Various authors--Notebooks logging Genie's behavior, 1974 June 8-1976 June 12 (Box 75, Folder 6)
    - Typed collation of notes from various authors, 1974 July (Box 75, Folder 7)
    - Typed collation of notes from various authors, 1974 August (Box 75, Folder 8)
    - Typed collation of notes from various authors, 1974 September (Box 75, Folder 9)
    - Typed collation of notes from various authors, 1974 October (Box 76, Folder 1)
    - Typed collation of notes from various authors, 1974 November (Box 76, Folder 2)
    - Typed collation of notes from various authors, 1974 November-December (Box 76, Folder 3)
      Includes December notes from Irene Wiley.
    - Genie's response to live music and other noted behavior, ca. 1975 (Box 76, Folder 4)
    - Rigler, David--various handwritten notes, ca. 1975-1993 (Box 76, Folder 5)
    - Owens, Larry--Notes on Genie's reading, 1975 January 14 (Box 76, Folder 6)
    - Rigler, Marilyn--Notebooks, 1975 May 17-1976 April 18 (Box 76, Folder 7)
      One composition notebook. Also includes inserted document entitled, "Lincoln School 1975."
    - Rigler, Marilyn--Notes from meeting with Bob Jacobs, 1976 January 23 (Box 76, Folder 8)
    - Curtiss, Susan--Typed narrative of observations, 1976 January 29 (Box 76, Folder 9)
    - Rigler, Marilyn--Observational notes, 1976 October 9; 1977 July 8-29 (Box 76, Folder 10)
    - Rigler, David--Various handwritten notes by David Rigler, ca. 1977 (Box 76, Folder 11)
    - Miscellaneous observational note about visit with Genie, 1977 January 2 (Box 76, Folder 12)
    - Rigler, David--Session notes, 1977 September 15 (Box 76, Folder 13)
    - Miscellaneous handwritten notes, ca. 1994 March (Box 76, Folder 14)
  - 8H. Testing, 1969-1975
    Subseries consists of material on various diagnostics including Q-sort and Playtest. Also includes Genie's results on tests administered.
    - Block, Jeanne--Test material, 1969 November-1973 October (Box 76, Folder 15)
    - Test score summaries, 1970-1973 (Box 76, Folder 16)
    - Summary of various tests and evaluations conducted on Genie, 1970-1975 (Box 76, Folder 17)
    - Preschool attainment record, 1970 November 6 (Box 76, Folder 18)
    - Various tests--Notes, 1970 November 6-1972 September 10 (Box 76, Folder 19)
    - Anton Brenner Developmental Gestalt Test of School Readiness, ca. 1971 (Box 76, Folder 20)
    - Block, Jeanne and Jack Block--California child Q-sort, ca. 1971 (Box 76, Folder 21)
    - Q-sort material, ca. 1971 (Box 77, Folder 1)
    - Pictures used for testing, 1971 (Box 77, Folder 2)
    - Test results from various diagnostics, 1971 (Box 77, Folder 3)
      Includes copies of Peabody Picture Vocabulary Test, WISC record form, preschool attainment record among others.
    - List of diagnostics administered to Genie, 1971-1973 (Box 77, Folder 4)
      Lists which team member administered the test.
    - Material and notes on Genie's drawing, painting, printing, and typing, 1971-1975 (Box 77, Folder 5)
    - Results of various diagnostics, 1971 February 2-1971 October 27 (Box 77, Folder 6)
      Includes intelligence, psycholinguistic, and vocabulary tests.
    - Cognitive evaluation--Correspondence and schedule of tests, 1971 May 24 (Box 77, Folder 7)
      From David Elkind, University of Rochester.
    - Games used with Genie, ca. 1971 November 30 (Box 77, Folder 8)
      Brief notes on Lotto Game, Puzzle No. 1, Puzzle No. 2
    - Material on comprehension tests, ca. 1972 (Box 77, Folder 9)
    - T-scope testing material, ca. 1972 (Box 77, Folder 10)
    - Results of various diagnostics, 1972 January 23-1972 October 17 (Box 77, Folder 11)
    - Frostig visual perception exercises, 1972 February 28; 1972 March 5 (Box 77, Folder 12)
    - Dichotic listening with Genie, 1972 March 27-1973 June 3 (Box 77, Folder 13)
    - Dichotic listening at the Childrens Hospital audiometry studio, 1972 May 10 (Box 77, Folder 14)
    - Writing/identification exercise [by Genie], 1972 May 17 (Box 77, Folder 15)
    - Kagan's matching familiar faces and figures, ca. 1973 (Box 77, Folder 16)
      Directions and other material.
    - Words and symbols--Note cards, ca. 1973 (Box 77, Folder 17)
    - Block, Jeanne and Jack Block--California child Q-sort, 1973 (Box 78, Folder 1)
    - Colors--Miscellaneous testing material, 1973 (Box 78, Folder 2)
    - Psychological and physical test results for Genie, 1973 January 27-1973 November 9; undated (Box 78, Folder 3)
      Includes auditory, verbal, and motor function results. Also includes pencils drawings by Genie.
    - Test results from various diagnostics, 1973 May 8-9 (Box 78, Folder 4)
    - UCLA Phonetics Lab test results, 1973 June 3 (Box 78, Folder 5)
    - Cratty, Bryant--Perceptual-motor abilities summary, 1973 June 5 (Box 78, Folder 6)
    - Tachistoscope study material, 1973 October 23 (Box 78, Folder 7)
    - Psychological evaluation of Genie by Cecile Falk, 1974 February 5-14 (Box 78, Folder 8)
    - Piaget-type procedures material from Read Tuddenham, 1974 May 14 (Box 78, Folder 9)
    - Instructions and Genie's results for "Playing with Parachute", 1974 July 15 (Box 78, Folder 10)
    - Playtest--Memorandum from Bernard [?], 1974 July 30 (Box 78, Folder 11)